Dan Higgins

Software Developer

07826173615 danhiggins23@outlook.com danhiggins.tech

PROFILE

Over the last 2 years, I've been involved in multiple projects for high-profile clients, developing my skills as a Software Developer primarily using React, AEM, Java and Cypress. I'm a confident and hardworking individual who is passionate about the IT industry and highly motivated to learn. I have a very broad skillset and have experiences using skills ranging from back-end (Java) & front-end development (React, ES6, SASS) to project management. I aim to pursue further opportunities within the industry to enable me to constantly learn and specialise my skills within Front-End Development.

EDUCATION

Teesside University

BSc Digital Forensics, 1st Class Honours

Open University

Introduction to Cyber Security

SKILLS

Front-end ReactJS AngularJS Javascript (ES6) HTML5 & CSS3 SASS & Less

Frameworks

JEST & JUNIT
Cucumber
Cypress
Selenium
Postman
React Test Utils

Testing

Back-end & Scripting

Styleguidist

Bootstrap

Java 8 & Java EE Mulesoft VBScript Bash

Databases

MySQL Oracel SQL MongoDB

Others

Git Jenkins Agile Scrum Waterfall TDD

IDE's

VS Code IntelliJ Eclipse PyCharm

EXPERIENCE

Santander, 2020-Present – Full Stack Developer

- Collaborating within an agile project within the Fraud Prevention department in Santech, following agile scrum ceremonies daily.
- Efficiently tested an internal node project end-to-end using Cypress and integrated automation into Jenkins Pipeline. I was also responsible for running regression tests using JUnit after code changes/deployments.
- Drove changes creating additional operators for internal rule engine project to allow additional rules to be added to place blocks on accounts/cards where applicable.
- Collaboratively maintained/improved Java microservices to manipulate payloads and add additional business logic.
- Gained a far clearer understanding of Continuous Integration with gitlab and Jenkins, ensuring pipelines passed before deployments and creating new pipelines within Jenkins.

BT, 2018-19 - AEM Developer

- Involved within 2 agile projects across BT, developing components for the support & mobile feature management/usage section of the BT Business site.
- Began developing components in Angular JS using HTL and then shortly moved to a React implementation.
- Transitioned into a single page application implementation within React, where I was producing components end-to-end, documenting each component utilising styleguidist and ensuring high test coverage by writing unit tests for each component using Jest.
- I was also following agile methodologies and ceremonies daily and became very familiar with this process.

QA Consulting, 2018-Present – Consultant

- Gained a vast amount of technical & soft skills and had many opportunities to put them into practise during my 3 months training.
- Carried out many different projects in multiple technologies, such as a Bank GUI Application written in Java 8 and using MySQL to store users, a CV management system written in React and connected to a MYSQL database using spring boot and many others.

INTERESTS







Film & TV



SOCIAL MEDIA



danhiggins.tech



linkedin.com/in/danhiggins23

Ford Motor Company, 2017 - Project Manager

- During this 3-month summer placement as Project Manager at Ford, I was involved in multiple different IT infrastructure projects, responsible for holding meetings with world-wide clients, working with large amounts of capital.
- * Personally solely managed a pilot project for the company and brought a project from Red status to Green in my time at Ford, in which I collaboratively managed a remote team in the United States.
- During this time, I got very accustomed to using software such as WebEx and developing my ability to make relationships over the phone.

Civil Service, 2016 – Cyber Security Placement

- Gathered great knowledge during this 6-week summer placement, both practical and theoretical, including Network Management, TCP/IP, OSI model and cyber security etc.
- Learnt Python during my time here and became familiar with IDE's such as PyCharm.
- Provided with a USB Rubber Ducky (Pentest tool) and began to learn the simple language to perform different penetration testing actions.